Guide to the Henry R. Luce Papers 1894-2004 (bulk, 1932-1967) MS 3014
New-York Historical Society
- Series V. Subject Name Files, 1894-1995 (bulk 1933-1967); 30.1 Linear feet
  - Subseries V.A. Name Files A, 1894-1995 (bulk 1933-1967)
    - Jones, Jesse H., 1935-1948 (Box 90, Folder 6)
    - Jones, Joseph, 1943-1949 (Box 90, Folder 6)
    - Jones, Sam and Louise, 1947-1955 (Box 90, Folder 7)
    - Judd, Charles H., 1938 (Box 90, Folder 7)
      Includes letters of introduction for Judd from Robert T. Crane, Charles W. Eliot 2nd, and Max Farrand.
    - Judd, Walter H., 1945-1966 (Box 90, Folder 7)
      Includes a printed copy of the speech "What is the Truth About China?," and correspondence from Charles Edison and Marvin Liebman regarding the nomination of Judd for Vice President of the United States in 1960.
    - K - General (folder 1 of 2), 1937-1975 (Box 90, Folder 8)
      Includes #55 of the publication The Hour and an advance proof of the editorial "Inside Nazi Germany, 1938" from Boxoffice by Maurice Kann. Correspondents include Danny Kaye, Kenneth B. Keating, James G. Keller.
    - K - General (folder 2 of 2), 1933-1967 (Box 91, Folder 1)
      Includes the publication The Jerusalem News dated April 9, A.D. 30. as a parody of what the news would have looked like back then. Correspondents include Deborah Kerr, Lord Keynes, Ernest Joseph King, and Norman T. Kirk.
    - Kaiser, Henry J., 1945-1963 (Box 91, Folder 2)
    - Kefauver, Estes, 1947-1963 (Box 91, Folder 2)
    - Keller, Professor A. G., 1937-1946 (Box 91, Folder 2)
      Contains mostly correspondence between HRL and his former Yale professor on politics, print media, and other topics. Includes form membership letter for the William Graham Sumner Club and the pamphlet "The Simple Truth: Mark Granite Sizes Up Franklin Roosevelt."
    - Kennan, George F., 1963-1972 (Box 91, Folder 2)
      Contains copies of articles and one original letter of gratitude.
    - Kennedy, Edward M., 1963 (Box 91, Folder 2)
    - Kettaneh, Francis, 1949-1963 (Box 91, Folder 3)
      Includes the memorandum "A Proposed Solution of the Palestinian Refugee Problem," a signed carbon copy of a letter sent by Kettaneh to Anthony Eden, and a letter in French concerning the situation in Lebanon.
    - King, Cecil, 1963-1974 (Box 91, Folder 3)
    - Kiplinger, W. M., 1935-1963 (Box 91, Folder 3)
    - Klein, General Julius, 1954-1967 (Box 91, Folder 4)
      Includes a copy of a letter from Admiral Halsey to General MacArthur, two chapters from an unidentified manuscript stamped "confidential," and the journal Der Spiegel with Konrad Adenauer on the cover.
    - Klein, Dr. Julius, 1933-1966 (Box 91, Folder 5)
    - Kn-Kw - General, 1933-1967 (Box 91, Folder 6)
      Correspondents include Fred Korth.
    - Knight, Richard A., 1939-1958 (Box 91, Folder 7)
      Includes the pamphlet "A Petition to the Congress of the United States for the Redress of a Grievance Occasioned by the Corruption of the United States Supreme Court (As Constituted on March 6, 1944)."
    - Knopf, Alfred A., 1942-1949 (Box 91, Folder 7)
    - Knox, Frank E., 1936-1943 (Box 91, Folder 7)
      Includes a 15 December 1941 press release from the Navy Department "Brief Report of Conduct of Naval Personnel During Japanese Attack, Pearl Harbor, T.H., December 7, 1941."
    - Knox, William E., 1948-1963 (Box 91, Folder 7)
    - Kohlberg, Alfred J., 1944-1957 (Box 91, Folder 8)
      Includes the article "My Dream of World History; 1945-1975 by Earl Browder" possibly written by Kohlberg, and a carbon copy of a letter from Burton Rascoe.
    - Kommer, Rudolph (Dr.), 1939-1942 (Box 91, Folder 8)
    - Koo, Wellington, 1943-1986 (Box 91, Folder 8)
      Includes a confidential "Memorandum on American Policy Toward China."
    - Kobler, John, 1950-1968 (Box 92, Folder 1)
      Contains mostly correspondence, memoranda, and interview reports dealing with The Saturday Evening Post article on HRL. Also includes a letter from Boris Artzybasheff and a photograph of an HRL portait.
    - Kornitzer, Bela, 1948-1961 (Box 92, Folder 2)
      Includes a foreword to Kornitzer's book Father and Son by Dr. Eugene Sipocz, and a postcard with the image of the White House.
    - Kotelawala, Sir John, 1954 (Box 92, Folder 2)
      Contains correspondence and memoranda regarding a dinner in honor of Kotelawala, and a report on rubber.
    - Krock, Arthur, 1939-1963 (Box 92, Folder 2)
    - Kung, H. H., 1944-1973 (Box 92, Folder 2)
      Includes a memorandum on Hans Kung.
    - Krupp, Alfred, 1957-1964 (Box 92, Folder 2)
    - L - General, 1932-1967 (Box 92, Folder 3)
      Separated Materials
      Includes the brochure "A Letter of Desperation" from the World Neighbors, Inc., and the weekly publication Foreign Correspondence. Correspondents include Charles M. LaFollette, Bert Lahr, Frank C. Laubach, Bobby Layne, Lord Leathers, and Herbert H. Lehman.
    - Lamont, Thomas S. and Thomas W., 1933-1967 (Box 92, Folder 4)
      Includes a carbon copy of the "Report on Current Situation in China" by John Hersey? and a memorandum regarding British and American imperialism.
    - Larson, Arthur, 1956-1963 (Box 92, Folder 4)
    - LaRouche, Chester, 1943-1965 (Box 92, Folder 4)
      Includes a detailed letter regarding business and businessmen.
    - Laski, Harold, 1945-1967 (Box 92, Folder 4)
      Includes copies of excerpts from Laski's book The American Democracy.
    - Lasswell, Professor Harold D., 1939-1963 (Box 92, Folder 5)
      Includes the memorandum "Needed Research in Communication."
    - Latourette, Kenneth S., 1949-1950 (Box 92, Folder 5)
    - Lattimore, Owen, 1950-1972 (Box 92, Folder 5)
      Contains copies of clippings and a cross reference sheet.
    - Lawrence, David, 1933-1940 (Box 92, Folder 5)
      Includes a carbon copy of the article "The Coming Crisis" and financial memoranda regarding "United States News."
    - Lazareff, Pierre, 1956-1972 (Box 93, Folder 1)
    - Lazo, Mario, 1946-1951 (Box 93, Folder 1)
      Includes a memorandum in Spanish regarding LIFE in Latin America with hand-drawn potential logos.
    - Leiper, Henry Smith, 1938-1960 (Box 93, Folder 1)
      Includes a broadside on Dr. Hans W. Weigert from The League for Fair Play.
    - Levitas, S. M., 1947-1960 (Box 93, Folder 1)
      Includes a printed copy of "Cable to Ernest Bevin."
    - Li-Ly - General, 1933-1967 (Box 93, Folder 2)
      Includes a typescript copy of a letter from Dorothy Thompson to D. A. Lindsay, a telegram from William Benton to Lloyd George, a letter from Walter H. Judd to Edwin C. Lobenstine, and the pamphlet "Serious Question for Serious Voters at a Serious Time" from Oswald B. Lord regarding the 1940 presidential election. Correspondents include Trygve Lie, Charles A. Lindbergh, and Harold Lloyd.
    - Libes, Martin, 1953-1959 (Box 93, Folder 3)
      Includes the memorandum "Shake-up in Moscow."
    - Lilienthal, David E., 1948-1970 (Box 93, Folder 3)
      Includes commencement addresses delivered by Lilienthal titled "Science and the Spirit of Man" and "The Citizen as Public Servant."
    - Lim, Robert K. S., 1944 (Box 93, Folder 3)
      Includes programs from an honorary dinner for Lim and United China Relief printed materials.
    - Lin Yutang, 1937-1956 (Box 93, Folder 3)
      Includes drafts of articles "First Exclusive Inside Story of Sian Kidnap" and "Death of a University."
    - Linen, Jr. James, 1936-1949 (Box 93, Folder 4)
      Includes the pamphlet "Education for World Understanding," and a memorandum on post-war China and the use of international correspondence schools.
    - Lippman, Walter, 1937-1963 (Box 93, Folder 4)
      Includes the memorandum "Walter Lippmann's Foreign Policy."
    - Liu, Frank (folder 1 of 2), 1945-1959 (Box 93, Folder 5)
      Contains memoranda titled "A Concrete Anti-Communism Program in the Far East Operations Belly" and "What Would the Communists be up to in China and the Far East?"
    - Liu, Frank (folder 2 of 2) - oversize, 1939 (Box OS-Large)
      Contains a 40''x30'' map labeled "New China Map" published by Jin-Sin Geographic Institute, Shanghai, 1939.
    - Lloyd, Selwyn, 1962 (Box 93, Folder 5)
      Includes the memorandum "Price of Gold."
    - Lodge, John, 1951-1956 (Box 93, Folder 5)
    - Loeb, Gerald M., 1940-1952 (Box 93, Folder 5)
      Includes memoranda on the stock, profitability and general finances of Time Inc.
    - Lorant, Stephan, 1937-1971 (Box 93, Folder 5)
    - Lothian, Lord, 1940 (Box 93, Folder 6)
      Includes a memorandum on World War II and the British navy.
    - Lovell, Malcolm, 1941 (Box 93, Folder 6)
    - Lovett, Robert A., 1935-1963 (Box 93, Folder 6)
    - Lowry, C. W., 1952-1966 (Box 94, Folder 1)
      Includes the sermon "Christianity's Answer to Communism," a preface to the second edition of the book Communism and Christ, the documentary brief "Conflicting Faiths: Christianity Versus Communism," an "Open Letter to the Perplexed Among Communists," a copy of the statement "Our Vietnam Commitment: The Common Calling of Americans," and a carbon copy of a letter from Lowry to the German People and Chancellor Konrad Adenauer.
    - Luce, Henry R. - Letters to Family, circa 1957-1980 (Box 94, Folder 1)
      Contains excerpts from HRL letters to his first wife Lila Luce Tyng, and excerpts and copies of his family correspondence from 1903-1922.
    - Luce, Earle D., 1939-1942 (Box 94, Folder 1)
    - Luce, Elizabeth R., 1942-1948 (Box 94, Folder 2)
      Includes a photograph of Elizabeth Luce with two unidentified men at the opening of China House, and copies of correspondence and prayers from HRL's mother and his replies. Also includes a copy of an account from J.C. Owen of saving the Luce family during the Boxer Rebellion in China, and copies of the letters of condolences following Elizabeth's death.
    - Luce, Emmavail, 1985 (Box 94, Folder 2)
      Contains a copy of a newspaper clipping of her obituary.
    - Luce, Elisabeth, circa 1932-1967 (Box 94, Folder 2)
      Contains a one sentence note on her marriage.
    - Luce, Henry W. - Photographs and Biography, 1942-1944 (Box 94, Folder 2)
      Includes photographs and negatives of HRL's father, and excerpts from a Sheldon R. Luce letter.
    - Luce, Henry W. - Memorial Book (3 folders), circa 1941-1942 (Box 94, Folder 3-5)
      Six copies of the hardcover memorial book Henry Winter Luce.
    - Luce, Henry W. - Miscellaneous, 1894-1968 (Box 94, Folder 6)
      Includes copies of Henry W. Luce correspondence from the Archives of the Student Volunteer Movement for Foreign Missions and the Archives of the United Board for Christian Higher Education in Asia, as well as original correspondence including a 14 September 1923 letter to H. L. Banghart where TIME Magazine is mentioned. Also includes a copy of "My Credo, with reference to China and its Christian Colleges."
    - Luce, Howard V., 1936-1948 (Box 94, Folder 7)
    - Luce, Peter Paul, 1949-1967 (Box 94, Folder 7)
    - Lunn, Arnold, 1949 (Box 94, Folder 7)
      Includes galleys from the "Ski Year Book."
    - Lyons, Leonard, 1944-1946 (Box 94, Folder 7)
    - M - General, 1933-1967 (Box 95, Folder 1)
      Correspondents include Hisakichi Maeda, Mickey Mantle (copy), Harpo Marx, Mrs. Raymond Massey, Francis P. Matthews
    - MacArthur, II Douglas, 1946-1967 (Box 95, Folder 2)
    - Magrauth, Joseph W., 1932-1933 (Box 95, Folder 2)
      Includes correspondence with suggestions of starting a department on law in TIME.
    - Malagodi, Giovanni, 1955-1957 (Box 95, Folder 2)
      Includes summaries of conversations with Malagodi.
    - Malik, Charles, 1949-1965 (Box 95, Folder 2)
      Includes correspondence from A. M. Lederer, and a statement made by Malik before the Political Committee of the General Assembly titled "War and Peace."
    - Mansure, Edmund, 1954-1955 (Box 95, Folder 3)
    - Marcosson, Isaac F., 1936-1955 (Box 95, Folder 3)
    - Martin, Edward, 1944-1963 (Box 95, Folder 3)
    - Martin, Jr. Joseph W., 1940-1966 (Box 95, Folder 3)
      Includes a copy of an outline of an unfinished 111-page manuscript Memoirs of Henry R. Luce.
    - Marzotto, Gaetano, 1955 (Box 95, Folder 3)
    - Matter, Enrico, 1955 (Box 95, Folder 4)
    - Matthews, Roland (Mr. and Mrs.), 1950-1952 (Box 95, Folder 4)
      Includes a copy of the publication Survey: Confidential Newsletter.
    - Maxwell, Elsa, 1943-1957 (Box 95, Folder 4)
      Includes a Radio Report Inc. interview excerpt titled "Elsa Relates Matchmaking of Henry and Clare Luce."
    - Mayer, Louis B., 1941-1942 (Box 95, Folder 4)
    - Mayes, Herbert, 1959-1973 (Box 95, Folder 4)
    - Mc - General, 1933-1967 (Box 95, Folder 5)
      Includes the broadside "Business Stands Against War," and a carbon copy of a letter from E.D. McMahon to President Roosevelt regarding World War II. Correspondents include James J. McCaffrey, John Alex McCone, John W. McCormack, James H. McGraw Jr., and General McNarney.
    - McCauliff, George A., 1953-1954 (Box 95, Folder 6)
      Includes a draft of the article "Day of Jubilee" as part of the religion section by Douglas Auchincloss, and correspondence related to the magazine Jubilee.
    - McCloy, John, 1941-1965 (Box 95, Folder 6)
      Includes the brochure "Vote Yes: Modern Courts for Modern Justice," and a letter from Hamilton Fish Armstrong.
    - McCormick, Ada (folder 1 of 2), 1942-1944 (Box 95, Folder 7)
      Includes printed materials.
    - McCormick, Ada (folder 2 of 2), 1943-1944 (Box 96, Folder 1)
      Contains three issues of the publication Letter.
    - McCormick, Fowler, 1955-1973 (Box 96, Folder 2)
    - McCormick, Robert R., 1942-1949 (Box 96, Folder 2)
      Includes a letter from J. H. Sawyer, Jr.
    - McCoy, Judge Philbrick, 1961-1963 (Box 96, Folder 2)
    - McCrary, John Reagan (Tex), 1952-1958 (Box 96, Folder 2)
      Includes a copy of a letter from President Eisenhower.
    - McCullagh, Clement George, 1941-1952 (Box 96, Folder 2)
    - McDonald, Jr. E. F., 1948 (Box 96, Folder 2)
      Includes a page proof advertisement for a hearing aid.
    - McHenry, James, 1933-1951 (Box 96, Folder 2)
    - Me-Mi - General (folder 1 of 2), 1937-1967 (Box 96, Folder 3)
      Includes a copy of the article "Military Business and the Arms Race" by Stanislav Menshikov with related correspondence, and issues of the publication Propaganda Analysis: A Monthly Letter to Help the Intelligent Citizen Detect and Analyze Propaganda from Clyde R. Miller, Secretary of the Institute for Propaganda Analysis. Correspondents include George V. Melas, G.S. Meloy Jr., H.L. Mencken (telegram), and Lauritz Melchior.
    - Mi - General (folder 2 of 2), 1942-1965 (Box 96, Folder 4)
      Includes issues of the newsletter The Messenger from Richmond P. Miller. Correspondents include J. Irwin Miller and Wilbur D. Mills.
    - Meek, Samuel, 1936-1950 (Box 96, Folder 5)
    - Mehta, Gaganvihari Lallubhai, 1953 (Box 96, Folder 5)
      Includes a letter from Eric Johnston, President of the Motion Picture Association of America, Inc.
    - Merz, Charles, 1940-1949 (Box 96, Folder 5)
    - Meyer, Eugene (Mr. and Mrs.), 1937-1955 (Box 96, Folder 5)
      Includes the pamphlet "British Home Front" by Agnes E. Meyer.
    - Millis, Walter, 1940-1954 (Box 96, Folder 5)
    - Mo-My - General, 1933-1967 (Box 96, Folder 6)
      Includes a photograph of Charles S. Mott and HRL speaking at a China Relief event. Correspondents include Charles Mohr, Ward Morehouse, deLesseps S .Morrison, Elizabeth C. Morrow, Lewis Mumford, Frank Murphy, and Edward R. Murrow.
    - Mondadori, Arnaldo, 1953-1971 (Box 97, Folder 1)
    - Moore, Garrett, 1952 (Box 97, Folder 1)
      Includes an issue of the magazine History Today.
    - Moran, Breck, 1940 (Box 97, Folder 2)
      Includes the 7 February 1940 issue of the newspaper The Cody Enterprise.
    - Morano, Albert P., 1947-1959 (Box 97, Folder 2)
      Includes a letter from Carroll D. Kearns, text of the address made by Morano at the Bridgeport Chamber of Commerce luncheon, and copies of correspondence dealing with requests to appoint Clare Boothe Luce as Secretary of State.
    - Morgenthau, Jr. Henry, 1938-1963 (Box 97, Folder 2)
      Includes a draft from the Letters section of TIME titled "Morgenthau's Forecast" which was not published.
    - Morlion, Father Felix, 1954-1965 (Box 97, Folder 2)
      Includes a memorandum on the study project "The Philosophy and Practice of Private Enterprise in America and Italy."
    - Moses, Robert, 1933-1965 (Box 97, Folder 2)
      Includes carbon copies of correspondence between Moses and Guy Greer regarding post-war employment and public works.
    - N - General, 1935-1967 (Box 97, Folder 3)
      Includes a copy of a letter from HRL to Mohammed Naguib, and the speech "The Mission of the Liberal Arts" by Roy F. Nichols. Correspondents include Stephen C. Neill, Arthur C. Nielsen, Samuel I. Newhouse Jr., Harold Nicolson, and Isamu Noguchi.
    - Nast, Condé, 1933-1941 (Box 97, Folder 4)
      Includes the memorandum (possibly a retyped copy) "To the Vanity Fair Editors Concerning Their Suggestion to Turn Vanity Fair Into a Pictorial Weekly" which mentions Clare Brokaw (Clare Boothe Luce).
    - Needham, Maurice, 1956-1962 (Box 97, Folder 4)
    - Nehru, Madame Rajan K., 1963 (Box 97, Folder 4)
    - Niarchos, Stavros S., 1957-1963 (Box 97, Folder 4)
      Includes a "Summary of the Proceedings in the U.S.A. and England Between Sun Oil Company and World Tankers Corporation."
    - Nicolini, Franco, 1953 (Box 97, Folder 4)
      Includes HRL's interview with the Italian publication Valori titled "A Conversation With the Editor of FORTUNE on the Fortune of the Press."
    - Nimitz, Admiral Chester W., 1943-1963 (Box 97, Folder 4)
      Includes part of the script from the "March of Time" program with the statement made by Nimitz.
    - Norris, Charles G., 1938-1943 (Box 97, Folder 4)
    - Norton, Henry K., 1936 (Box 97, Folder 4)
    - O - General, 1933-1967 (Box 97, Folder 5)
      Correspondents include Lawrence F. O'Brien, Culbert L. Oslon, Sir David Ormsby Gore, and G. Bromley Oxnam.
    - O'Donnell, Emmet, 1951 (Box 97, Folder 6)
      Contains the foreword of an unidentified manuscript regarding the activities of the FEAF Bomber Command in the Korean War.
    - O'Hara, John, 1938-1949 (Box 97, Folder 6)
    - Olivetti, Roberto, 1953-1955 (Box 97, Folder 6)
    - On Kin, 1952 (Box 97, Folder 6)
      Includes a letter from Lyman Hoover of the Committee for a Free Asia, and correspondence and memoranda regarding the lunch in honor of the editor of The Burma Times.
    - Orton, William A., 1948 (Box 97, Folder 6)
      Includes the first draft of the article "Business and Ethics."
    - Oxnam, G. Bromley, 1947-1957 (Box 97, Folder 6)
    - P - General, 1933-1967 (Box 97, Folder 7)
      Correspondents include Shah Pahlavi (copy), Paul Theodore Prince Paleologue, Sandro Pallavicini, Arnold Palmer, Robert P. Patterson, and Linus Pauling.
    - Page, Arthur, 1933-1948 (Box 98, Folder 1)
    - Page, Ruth, 1950 (Box 98, Folder 1)
    - Palmer, Carleton H. and Winthrop B., 1936-1957 (Box 98, Folder 1)
      Includes a form letter to E.R. Squibb & Sons salesmen regarding advertising in early issues of LIFE, and an advertising brochure for the magazine Poetry London-New York.
    - Parker, G. B., 1935-1943 (Box 98, Folder 1)
    - Palmer, Paul, 1935-1937 (Box 98, Folder 1)
    - Paepke, Walter, 1936-1955 (Box 98, Folder 1)
      Includes a page proof of an advertisement for the Container Corporation of America drawn by Mei Mei Sze.
    - Parmentier, Douglas, 1938 (Box 98, Folder 1)
    - Parton, James, 1948 (Box 98, Folder 1)
      Includes an unsigned pre-incorporation subscription agreement for Independence, Inc. a Time Inc. venture into Los Angeles newspapers.
    - Patterson, Grove, 1940-1951 (Box 98, Folder 2)
      Includes the address delivered at the Convention of the Association of National Advertisers "The Shield of Democracy" in pamphlet form.
    - Patterson, Morehead, 1948-1962 (Box 98, Folder 2)
    - Patterson, Jr. Richard C., 1945-1959 (Box 98, Folder 2)
    - Paul VI (Pope), 1965-1966 (Box 98, Folder 2)
      Contains memoranda and correspondence dealing with publications resulting from the Pope's visit to the United States.
    - Pawley, William D., 1943-1952 (Box 98, Folder 2)
      Includes correspondence dealing with the political situation in Brazil and Latin America.
    - Pe-Ph - General, 1933-1967 (Box 98, Folder 3)
      Includes carbon copies of correspondence addressed to Westbrook Pegler. Correspondents include Gregory Peck, Ferdinand Pecora, J. C. Penney, Claude Pepper, Frances Perkins, Prince Peter of Greece, and Field Marshal A. Papagos.
    - Peden, Allen, 1933 (Box 98, Folder 4)
    - Pell, Claiborne, 1965 (Box 98, Folder 4)
    - Pella, Guiseppe (Premier), 1953-1955 (Box 98, Folder 4)
      Includes a letter from Pella to Giovanni Fummi.
    - Penton, Brian, 1944 (Box 98, Folder 4)
    - Percy, Charles H., 1959-1967 (Box 98, Folder 4)
    - Phelps, William Lyon, 1942-1943 (Box 98, Folder 4)
      Includes three photographs of barges and ships on the Mississippi River.
    - Pi-Py - General, 1933-1967 (Box 98, Folder 5)
      Correspondents include Mary Pickford, Charles Poletti, Lily Pons, Cole Porter, Charles E. Potter, Ralph F. Gates, and Pyo Wook Han.
    - Pike, James A., 1961-1964 (Box 98, Folder 6)
      Contains correspondence mostly regarding the Christian Anti-Communist Crusade.
    - Pitman, Paul, 1952-1963 (Box 98, Folder 6)
    - Pitzele, Merlyn S., 1948-1950 (Box 98, Folder 6)
      Includes typed notes of an interview with HRL for an article in Business Week.
    - Poling, Daniel, 1947-1964 (Box 98, Folder 6)
    - Pope, Arthur U., 1943-1949 (Box 98, Folder 6)
    - Porter, Charles O., 1959-1960 (Box 98, Folder 6)
    - Powel, Hartford, 1933-1948 (Box 98, Folder 7)
    - Price, Harry B. (Mr. and Mrs.), 1938-1955 (Box 98, Folder 7)
      Includes a page proof of the Gallup Poll article "Boycott of Japan and Embargo on War Materials Favored as U.S. Sympathy for China Rises," the paper "Pacific Strategy: A Key to American Defense," the booklet "Shall America Stop Arming Japan," and correspondence with memoranda from The American Committee for Non-Participation in Japanese Aggression.
    - Pulitzer, Jr. Joseph, 1938-1951 (Box 98, Folder 7)
    - Q - General, 1947-1967 (Box 99, Folder 1)
    - Quaroni (Ambassador), 1955 (Box 99, Folder 2)
      Includes a speech? in Italian titled "La Coesistenza" (coexistence) with a partial translation.
    - Quezon, Manuel, 1941-1943 (Box 99, Folder 2)
    - Ra-Re - General, 1933-1965 (Box 99, Folder 3)
      Correspondents include Ralph T. Reed, James B. Reston, and Paul Reynaud.
    - Radford, Admiral Arthur, 1953-1963 (Box 99, Folder 4)
    - Ramirez, Ramiro and William, 1967 (Box 99, Folder 4)
    - Ramsaye, Terry, 1933 (Box 99, Folder 4)
    - Read, David, 1954-1966 (Box 99, Folder 4)
    - Reed, Guy E., 1950 (Box 99, Folder 4)
      Includes the speech "Why Business Men Should Organize to Destroy Organized Crime" by Reed made before the Economic Club of Detroit.
    - Reeves, Harrison, 1932-1940 (Box 99, Folder 4)
    - Reid, Mrs. Ogden, 1939-1965 (Box 99, Folder 4)
    - Reiser, Oliver, 1964-1974 (Box 99, Folder 4)
    - Reston, James, 1953-1963 (Box 99, Folder 4)
    - Rh-Ry - General, 1933-1974 (Box 99, Folder 5)
      Includes a postcard with the image of the Eskimo in skin omiak hunting walrus in Alaska sent by Kermit Roosevelt. Correspondents include Admiral H. G. Rickover, Donald W. Riegle Jr., Reuben B. Robertson Jr., James S. Rockefeller, General K. E. Rockey, Ginger Rogers, George Romney, James Roosevelt, Quentin Roosevelt II, and Rosalind Russell.
    - Rhyne, Charles - Speeches and Writings, 1958-1959 (Box 99, Folder 6)